[music]
Hi everyone and welcome to this session
on what's new in BCbench. My name is Yos
and I'm joined today with my colleague
>> Mharen.
>> Before we cover what's new in BCbench,
let's start with a recap on what BCbench
is and how we use it. BCBench is a
reproducible evaluation framework for AI
coding agents working on real world AI
development task inspired by SVBench.
This means [snorts] that we use it to
test the uh the agents and harnesses and
models that we use to develop um AL
features and bug fixes and we measure
the performance of these different
models and harnesses on real problems.
Um BCbench is there to quantify the
impact of tooling changes. So if we're
changing the tools or models or
instructions or agents that are working
on these coding problems, does uh the
result change? Do they get better or
worse over time? Um, and this in turn
allows us to track the progress with
comparable metrics over time. It also
makes it possible for us to iterate
rapidly. So if we see scores going up or
down because of a change we've made, we
can quickly revert or continue with a
certain change. Now why do we need our
own benchmarking tool in addition to
SWEBench? This is because the the
general coding benchmarks like SWEBench
don't uh reflect the AL development
realities. AL is a smaller ecosystem
than other uh coding languages
and there's a lot of domain specific
tooling for AL features. This is best
illustrated by simply looking at the
number of open- source repositories for
different coding languages in GitHub. As
you can see, there's only 400 um that
are written in AL. Well, there's 3.3
million in Python and 650,000 in C. So,
what do we cover with BCBench? So today
BCbench covers the following categories
of AL development work. First of all,
there's bug fixing and there's test
generation and also there's PR reviews
or code reviews. And throughout these
categories, BC bench follows the
principles of representative real world
data sets. Meaning that the data sets
that are part of this benchmark come
from real books and real PRs and real
tests uh that were written in AL uh that
BCbench runs on. These data sets are
open source, meaning that BC bench can
run can be run transparently and the
results can be reproduced by anyone that
runs this uh benchmark. And finally, we
make sure that these evaluations are
rigorous by following industry best
practices. In this session, we don't
have the opportunity to go into the deep
details of how BCBench was built, uh how
it works and why it works. If you are
interested in learning the details of
this, we have published a research paper
on aka.ms/bcbench
paper that is available uh for all to
read uh that contains all the details.
Thanks. A quick recap on the since last
time we were here we introduced the bug
fixing category. Um as used covered um a
quick recap of what it is about. An
agent is tasked with fixing a bug in the
real codebase just like how human
engineers are deal with day-to-day.
Uh and we uh use 101 tasks from the real
box where real human engineer solve in
our n repositories and busy
[clears throat] apps.
And finally, uh if you notice it,
haven't noticed it, uh there is the
ALMCP server that uh thanks to our
beloved developer experience team that
expose AL development tools like
compiling, publishing and simple search
to those coding agents. So you don't
need to open your visual studio code and
the agents will have the capability to
um publish and um compel just like uh
what our engineers do dayto-day.
So what has the result uh showed us?
Um during over the last few months we
have done lots of experiments and find
out uh using the GitHub copilot CLI and
cloud opus for six uh we can we find
that AMCP uh gives the coding agents a
meaningful improvement over uh when the
coding agent don't have access to it. As
you can see that um the pass head five
matrix improved almost 10%. Uh and
there's also a significant improvement
uh in the mean resolution rate. Well, it
does take a bit longer but I think that
makes sense because the agent now has to
uh publish apps and uh and run tests and
things like that.
Uh what else did we discover? uh we find
that um and using the same model and but
with different agent harnesses like
GitHub copilot CLI versus cloud code uh
we find no significant differences uh
between them. Uh all the numbers are
fairly close when using the same models.
So the choice of models probably matter
more than the choice of agent harness at
least using our data set. And what else
did we do? uh over the last few months
we got lots of questions about now that
uh our repositories are open source
because we want to be transparent
there is a risk of the models will be
trained on the public available data so
they will memorize our solutions and
that is called uh contamination
we um followed a precedence using this
paper it's a three bench illusion so for
folks who are interested give it a read.
Uh we follow their method uh as much as
possible
and uh derived a contamination detection
strategy of our own.
So how does it work? uh we give them a
template, give the coding agent a
template where we uh uh feed it with
where which repository is this task
coming from like for example BC apps and
a problem statement uh the buck
description just like on the accuracy
test part and finally we ask the coding
agent to come up with the file is
supposed to modify but this time without
the code base itself. So there's no way
the coding agent can figure this out by
itself except for memorize it from the
training. And what is the result? Here
is a run a rerun in one of our tasks
where the agent managed to uh response
with a fairly close uh file path that
looks correct. Uh but um as you can see
the file is supposed to modify our our
three files and uh even the closest one
did not match exactly. So it deduced the
path from the bug description but did
not memorize the exact file path.
As some of us may be wondering now all
our source code on PC apps maybe the
agent managed to figure out from there
that is not the case either uh because
on PC apps the the file path starts a
bit differently too than uh what the
agent managed to come up with. So for
this specific example, we we decide the
agent didn't manage to memorize the
problem. So this specific task was not
contaminated. And here are the results
uh over 101 tasks in our data set. We
chose three models. Um and they are
chosen because their knowledge cut off
date uh is after we made BCbench public.
So they had a chance to memorize our
data set and the solutions and as you
can see the all for all three models
they only managed to uh come up with one
out of 101 tasks uh that's a match and
in this specific case it was actually
the task actually contain the exact file
path is supposed to modify
and with that this is not a one-time
effort we will be continuous
continuously monitoring the signs of
contamination in BCB bench to make sure
our data reflect the performance of the
models and the agent but not the how the
model remembers our data set and uh you
mentioned previously there is a new uh
code review category that we have on
boarded to BCbench
and I want to cover a bit more details
here
uh the motivation for us to introduce
use the code view category is because we
are getting more and more poll requests
on BC apps. As you can see from the
screenshot here that um
uh the number of poll requests on BC
apps are growing very fast especially
now that we have all the source code uh
on BC apps. So a natural question we
come up with is now that AI can help us
create those poll requests, can AI help
us review the AL code changes as well.
So uh this doesn't become a bottleneck.
So we implemented three way to review AL
pests um in BC bench. Uh they are all
slightly different. The first one is the
baseline or the the controlled
experiment where we use the barebone
GitHub copilot UI. Uh it doesn't have
any specialized AI knowledge. It just
download from uh internet directly.
And then we have the second approach of
BC quality where all um lots of our
partner community has been contributing
to with all the best practices and
things to pay attention to and we
installed that onto the copilot CLI
using the plug-in approach. So uh this
is the second uh way uh that we can
review AL pull requests. And finally
that our teams have been working on the
AL review agent. If you have contributed
to BC apps recently, you should see some
comments from this review agent that is
a specialized orchestration that um
designed to give BC quality a further
boost on focus on security, privacy and
performance. individually uh instead of
installing the BC quality all together
and how does the review uh methodology
works in BC bench. So here is a
simplified task we have uh for the code
review data set and the agent is tasked
to review this specific function that's
introduced in a poll request.
Uh and um for app developers you can
pause the video to see uh if you can
recognize uh what is the issue with this
code.
Uh and now uh we will uh review uh so
this is u for every task in the code
review data set it comes with the
expected comment meaning what is what is
wrong with this piece of code and in
this scenario is the log table uh line
that um is unnecessary because the whole
procedure is a read transaction so
there's no need for the log table here
in the code
and we run this specific task in our
pipeline and here are the results. Uh
the first one is from GPT56 Luna. He
categorized the issue to be cocurrency
and he left a comment that's um
semantically similar to uh what is
expected uh between line seven and 8 and
similarly GPT56 terror uh categorized
into a performance issue and then uh
left also similarly semantically on line
number seven.
So well the those uh comments uh looks
different but uh they both capture the
exact same expected comment. So here we
use a LM as judge. So different than the
bug fixing um category. Uh here we use
the LMS stretch to determine the
comments are uh expected and in both
scenario here we determine they are both
um generated the correct comment. At the
time of the recording of uh this um
session uh we are still working hard on
the results. Uh so please check back uh
on our GitHub repository uh if you're
curious. Now back to you.
>> Thank you Javan. So as a partner that is
um getting started with Aentic
engineering for your own uh apps in AL
you would want to experiment uh with the
tools instructions MCP server models
that you're using to do so. And to
experiment um you should visit our BC
bench repository on GitHub and first of
all check out the results that we
publish. So for the the test cases, the
bug fixes, the PR reviews, the test
generated uh that we publish, um there's
results that are there which already
should give you an idea of the models
and harnesses that are most effective at
developing in AL code. Of course, these
results are the results from running BCB
on our data set. Uh but what you want to
do is you want to fork our repository
and replace the data set that we have
created for our own AL app issues uh
with your own data set that includes
your own bug fixes, your own generated
tests and your own PRs. So you can see
how BCBench produces results for
different models and harnesses and tools
for your specific app problems.
Uh and then finally, as you do this, if
your repository uh is open source over
time, you want to make sure you check
for contamination as well. so that uh
newer models aren't trained on your open
source data set um as you rerun BCBench
in the future.
Um finally, this is the link where you
can find BCBench. You can find uh the
entire tool is open source. Our data set
is open source and also you can see the
results of our own BCBench runs. Uh the
link for this is
github.com/microsoft/bcbench.
And that concludes our session on
BCBench. Thanks everyone.
>> Thanks.